<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc SYSTEM "article.dtd">
<doc>
    <title>QShowDiff</title>
    <subtitle>QShowDiff is tool for visualisation of diffs generated from various VCS systems.</subtitle>

    <section>
        <title>About</title>

        <p lang="cs">
        QShowDiff je jednoduchy nastroj na barevne zobrazovani diffu. QShowDiff vznikl, protoze mi zde
        chybel nastroj, ktery by delal jen tuhle jednu vec. Sice zde existuji programy jako je
        <link url="http://kdiff3.sourceforge.net/">KDiff3</link> nebo
        <link url="http://www.caffeinated.me.uk/kompare/">Kompare</link>, ale ty jsou prilis komplikovane
        na tak jednoduchou vec jako je prohlizeni si diffu.
        </p>
        <p lang="en">
        QShowDiff is simple tool for colourful visualisation of diffs. QShowDiff was created because I was
        missing some tool which would do only this one thing. It's true that there are programs such as
        <link url="http://kdiff3.sourceforge.net/">KDiff3</link> or
        <link url="http://www.caffeinated.me.uk/kompare/">Kompare</link>, however these programs are too complicated
        for a task as simple as viewing diffs.
        </p>

        <p lang="cs">
        QShowDiff dela jen jednu vec a to je zobrazovani diffu. Neporovnava soubory ani adresare - od toho zde existuje
        mnoho nastroju, ktere to dokazi, a ktere to rozhodne delaji dobre. Proto take QShowDiff vznikl. Potreboval jsem
        program, ktery bude delat jenom tu jednu vec a to je zobrazovani barevneho diffu. Nic vic nic min.
        </p>
        <p lang="en">
        QShowDiff does only one thing and that is a visualisation of diff. It does not compare two files or directories - for
        that there are many tools that surely do the task very well. And that is the reason why QShowDiff was
        created. I needed a program which will do only one thing - colorful visualisation of diffs. Nothing more and nothing less.
        </p>

        <p lang="cs">
        Dalsi duvod proc vznikl je ten, ze by bylo fajn mit jeden nastroj pro zobrazeni diffu barevne, at
        se pouziva jakykoli verzovaci system. Tudiz jsem chtel QShowDiff naimplementovat tak, aby slo jednoduse
        pridavat podporu pro ruzne verzovaci systemy. Snad se mi to povedlo.
        </p>
        <p lang="en">
        Another reason for creating this program is that it would be nice to have only one tool for visualisation
        of diff from any version control system. So I wanted to implement QShowDiff to have simple interface
        for adding support for various version control systems. I hope it was answered.
        </p>

    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Usage</title>
        <p lang="cs">
        QShowDiff prijima jeden argument, coz je typ verzovaciho systemu, ze ktereho je zobrazovany diff generovan.
        Diff, ktery se ma zobrazovat je cten ze standartniho vstupu.
        </p>
        <p lang="en">
        QShowDiff takes only one argument, the type of VCS from which is visualised diff generated.
        Diff which has to be visualised is read from standart input.
        </p>

        <subsection>
            <title>Examples</title>

            <p lang="en">
                To show last changes in git repository
                <shell>
                    <command>git diff | qshowdiff git</command>
                </shell>
                <img alt="git screenshot" preview="preview-git.png" url="git.png" />
            </p>

            <p lang="en">
                To genrate patch from svn and visualise them later
                <shell>
                    <command>svn diff > changes.patch</command>
                    <command>cat changes.patch | qshowdiff svn</command>
                </shell>
                <img alt="svn screenshot" preview="preview-svn.png" url="svn.png" />
            </p>
        </subsection>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Source Code</title>
        <p lang="en">
        Latest development source code can be obtained from git repository http://www.danfis.cz/git/qshowdiff.git.
        <shell>
            <command>git clone http://www.danfis.cz/git/qshowdiff.git</command>
        </shell>
        </p>

        <p lang="en">
        You can also always browse the current contents of git repository on web using
        <link url="http://www.danfis.cz/cgi/gitweb?p=qshowdiff.git;a=summary">gitweb</link> or
        <link url="http://www.danfis.cz/cgi/cgit?r=qshowdiff">cgit</link>.
        </p>

        <p lang="en">
        Latest stable release can be downloaded from here: <link url="qshowdiff/qshowdiff-0.3.tar.gz">qshowdiff-0.3.tar.gz</link>
        </p>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Contact</title>
        <p lang="en">If you have any questions or suggestions how to improve this tool or if you have any patch you want to put
        to upstream feel free to contact me.</p>
        <p lang="en">&author; - <email>&email;</email></p>
    </section>
</doc>
<!-- /* vim: set sw=4 ts=4 et ft=xml tw=0 : */ -->
